[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "The sentence with correct punctuation--",
    "options": [
      "Maria my student is on leave today",
      "Maria, my student, is on leave today",
      "Maria my students is, on leave today",
      "Maria my students, is on leave today"
    ],
    "answer": "Maria, my student, is on leave today"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The antonym for 'Inimical' -",
    "options": ["Angry", "Indifferent", "Hostile", "Friendly"],
    "answer": "Friendly"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The synonym for 'efface' --",
    "options": ["rub out", "exhaust", "improve", "cut out"],
    "answer": "rub out"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The best passive from of the sentence :'We don't like idle people'-",
    "options": [
      "Idle people are not of our liking",
      "We are not liked by idle people",
      "Idle people are not like us",
      "Idle people are not liked by us"
    ],
    "answer": "Idle people are not liked by us"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "The correct sentence of the followings-",
    "options": [
      "The Nile is longest river in Africa",
      "The Nile is longest river in the Africa",
      "Nile is longest river in Africa",
      "The Nile is the longest river in Africa"
    ],
    "answer": "The Nile is the longest river in Africa"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Browning was the composer of any of the following poems-",
    "options": [
      "The Scholar Gipsy",
      "Andreadel Sarto",
      "Two Voices",
      "One one"
    ],
    "answer": "Andreadel Sarto"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "The right word to fit in the gaps of the flowing sentence- Give her a telephone number to ring ?..she gets lost?",
    "options": ["Unless", "Whether", "Incase", "Perhaps"],
    "answer": "Incase"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Synonym of 'Franchise'---",
    "options": ["Privilege", "Utility", "French", "Frankness"],
    "answer": "Privilege"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "The opposite word of 'Sluggish' --",
    "options": ["Dull", "Animated", "Heavy", "Slow"],
    "answer": "Animated"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "The correct spelling is-",
    "options": ["Humorous", "Humourious", "Humourous", "Humorious"],
    "answer": "Humorous"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Equivocation means--",
    "options": [
      "Equal opportunity to get a job",
      "Free expression of opinions",
      "Two contrary things in the same statement",
      "A true statement"
    ],
    "answer": "Two contrary things in the same statement"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Natural protein-এর কোড নাম-",
    "options": ["Protein-p 51", "Protein-p 49", "Protein-p 54", "Protein-p 53"],
    "answer": "Protein-p 49"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "When a person says he's 'all in' , it means----",
    "options": [
      "He has arrived",
      "He has finished packing",
      "He is very tired",
      "He has got everything"
    ],
    "answer": "He is very tired"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Bill of fare is-",
    "options": [
      "A valuable document",
      "A list of dishes at a restaurant",
      "A price list",
      "A chart of bus fair"
    ],
    "answer": "A list of dishes at a restaurant"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "A bull market means, that share prices are-",
    "options": ["Falling", "Moving", "Rising", "Statistic"],
    "answer": "Rising"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Blue chips are-",
    "options": [
      "Flat plastic countets used as money token",
      "Industrial shares considered to be a risky investment",
      "Securities issues by the government",
      "Industrial shares consideted to be a safe investment"
    ],
    "answer": "Industrial shares consideted to be a safe investment"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Razzmatazz means--",
    "options": [
      "A musical instrument",
      "A well-planned programme",
      "A noisy activity",
      "A musical drama"
    ],
    "answer": "A noisy activity"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Blockbuster means--",
    "options": [
      "Something that makes movement difficult",
      "A powerful explosive to demolish building",
      "A device to cut off a person?s head as a punishment",
      "A large solid peace of stone"
    ],
    "answer": "A powerful explosive to demolish building"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Any one of the flowing pairs are literary collaborators-",
    "options": [
      "Pope and Dryden",
      "Shelley and Keats",
      "Yeats and Eliot",
      "Eliot and pound"
    ],
    "answer": "Shelley and Keats"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "The correct sentence of the followings:",
    "options": [
      "A new cabinet has been sworn in Dhaka",
      "A new cabinet has been sworn by in Dhaka",
      "A new cabinet has sworn in Dhaka",
      "A new cabinet has been sworn at Dhaka"
    ],
    "answer": "A new cabinet has been sworn in Dhaka"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "To read between the lines means-",
    "options": [
      "To read carefully",
      "To read only some lines",
      "To read quickly to save times",
      "To read carefully to find out any hidden meanings"
    ],
    "answer": "To read carefully to find out any hidden meanings"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "The last word of the proverb, Handsome is that handsome-",
    "options": ["Works", "Thinks", "Does", "Says"],
    "answer": "Does"
  }
]
